<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on ramix.io</title>
    <link>https://ramix.io/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on ramix.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:53:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramix.io/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning 50 in Tech</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2017/11/turning-50-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:53:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2017/11/turning-50-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard for me to believe but it’s been half a century of “me”… and as we humans go through our hardware lifecycles, it’s good to take a pause and think about what it all means at some stages in the road.
Yes, it’s technically just another number. No more or less important than 14, 46 or 81. However, it has a soft meaning, a cultural significance, and its associated stereotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unintended Impact of Crashing my Phone</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2015/08/the-unintended-impact-of-crashing-my-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:01:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2015/08/the-unintended-impact-of-crashing-my-phone/</guid>
      <description>Yes, my really nice Samsung Galaxy Note 4, with an excellent camera, perfect size, and bright screen&amp;hellip;
Coming out of an Uber in front of my house at night, fell on a second curb that was put there for protection. I was about to give 5 stars to my driver, when baam! Face down. Since my phone was in my hand, it landed screen down with all my weight. The poor thing kept vibrating at random intervals with no other visible activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-term Elections</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2014/10/mid-term-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 07:32:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2014/10/mid-term-elections/</guid>
      <description>I grew up in Chile during the time of Pinochet, where &amp;lsquo;politics&amp;rsquo; was a bad word, and &amp;lsquo;politicians&amp;rsquo; were equivalent to &amp;lsquo;thugs&amp;rsquo;. Even after all these years and multiple iterations of democratically elected governments, people&amp;rsquo;s involvement in democracy is just limited to general elections every 5 years. Very little occurs in between.
You see, in my view, Chile is a place where the government does pretty much whatever it wants once it&amp;rsquo;s in power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>