<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ramix.io</title>
    <link>https://ramix.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ramix.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:12:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ramix.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete Linkwitz Setup</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2017/11/complete-linkwitz-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 16:12:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2017/11/complete-linkwitz-setup/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up to my previous post on how did I came to this place, so an interested reader should head there first.
After about a year of working on this on and off, I now have complete setup of the best work of Siegfried Linkwitz with a pair of LXMinis, a set of W-Frame subwoofer dipoles based also on his design, and the simply spectacular LX521.4 full range dipole speakers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning 50 in Tech</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2017/11/turning-50-in-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:53:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2017/11/turning-50-in-tech/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard for me to believe but it’s been half a century of “me”… and as we humans go through our hardware lifecycles, it’s good to take a pause and think about what it all means at some stages in the road.
Yes, it’s technically just another number. No more or less important than 14, 46 or 81. However, it has a soft meaning, a cultural significance, and its associated stereotypes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up CJDNS on pfSense</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2016/09/setting-up-cjdns-on-pfsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 15:30:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2016/09/setting-up-cjdns-on-pfsense/</guid>
      <description>CJDNS is an IPv6 encrypted mesh networking technology, used in Hyperborea and other mesh networks around the world. I particularly like the way it&amp;rsquo;s conceived, with end-to-end encryption, distributed IP address allocation, DHT-based source routing and MPLS-like label switching.
It has several interesting use cases, but I wanted to set it up in my pfSense gateway VM so I can use it as a distributed VPN of sorts. This could be useful to be able to access my systems from anywhere while traveling, or where my team can share access to each other&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Foundry labs, particularly when we travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Becoming a Gourmet Cook</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2016/07/on-becoming-a-gourmet-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 20:12:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2016/07/on-becoming-a-gourmet-cook/</guid>
      <description>I recently exchanged emails with a family member in Chile who was joking she couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine me in the kitchen, when she learned from my mom that I&amp;rsquo;m a self-proclaimed &amp;ldquo;gourmet cook&amp;rdquo;. I guess it makes sense. When I left Chile almost 20 years ago, my kitchen skills were really minimal, in spite of having grown up in a household where my mom cooked daily, and where my grandma Nicoletta, with her Italian heritage, made the most delicious dishes every time we visited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting the Right VPN Service</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2016/07/selecting-the-right-vpn-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 15:31:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2016/07/selecting-the-right-vpn-service/</guid>
      <description>I first published this in 2013 but since I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked recently by several friends, I figured I update it with more current information.
For the record, I’m a CISSP, and as such, computer security is always in the top of my mind. For me, that also extends to privacy.
Since I spend a good amount of time at airports, hotels, coffee shops and generally roaming around, having a VPN service has become a necessity for me as well as for anyone who values their online privacy and safety, even at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On my LXMini Speakers</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2016/02/on-my-lxmini-speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 19:23:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2016/02/on-my-lxmini-speakers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Not that long ago, I stumbled upon Siegfried Linkwitz&amp;rsquo;s web site when I was doing some research on speaker designs, and particularly open baffle systems. I became fascinated by his designs and ideas. His approach is different from the mainstream in the sense he goes down to basics, and starts by analyzing how we humans actually hear. In his web site, he states:
 “What you hear is not the air pressure variation in itself but what has drawn your attention is the two streams of superimposed air pressure variations at your eardrums”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Culture of Offending and Feeling Offended</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2015/12/the-culture-of-offending-and-feeling-offended/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 07:11:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2015/12/the-culture-of-offending-and-feeling-offended/</guid>
      <description>How many people have you offended today? None? How do you know?
In the overly politically correct environment we live in these days, it’s virtually impossible not to offend someone for some reason without ever intending to do so. All we can do is try, but chances are you will never know all the implications of a word, nuances, or even hand waving expressions.
I recently offended a Palestinian acquaintance by stating that a network design was ‘Kosher’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Politically Correct around Christmas</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2015/12/being-politically-correct-around-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 22:20:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2015/12/being-politically-correct-around-christmas/</guid>
      <description>The holidays are always a complicated time of the year, when one need to be extra cautious navigating the different cultural contexts for each and every person you care about, and much of society where we live our lives.
It can be really stressful and sometimes overwhelming to walk the fine line of saying what you feel or think openly (very much my nature), or use some more politically correct way that won’t offend others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unintended Impact of Crashing my Phone</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2015/08/the-unintended-impact-of-crashing-my-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:01:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2015/08/the-unintended-impact-of-crashing-my-phone/</guid>
      <description>Yes, my really nice Samsung Galaxy Note 4, with an excellent camera, perfect size, and bright screen&amp;hellip;
Coming out of an Uber in front of my house at night, fell on a second curb that was put there for protection. I was about to give 5 stars to my driver, when baam! Face down. Since my phone was in my hand, it landed screen down with all my weight. The poor thing kept vibrating at random intervals with no other visible activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting Together a Software-Centric Home Entertainment System</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2015/07/putting-together-a-software-centric-home-entertainment-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 17:12:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2015/07/putting-together-a-software-centric-home-entertainment-system/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been building home entertainment systems for more years I care to admit. It&amp;rsquo;s always been a hobby of mine and I find it extremely fun when things finally work as a whole, resulting in a complete operational system. I&amp;rsquo;ve never done it for money, but I&amp;rsquo;ve made them for friends and family and of course myself.
But in recent years, the dream of having all content in digital format, available on-demand at any point in any device has pretty much become a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-term Elections</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2014/10/mid-term-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 07:32:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2014/10/mid-term-elections/</guid>
      <description>I grew up in Chile during the time of Pinochet, where &amp;lsquo;politics&amp;rsquo; was a bad word, and &amp;lsquo;politicians&amp;rsquo; were equivalent to &amp;lsquo;thugs&amp;rsquo;. Even after all these years and multiple iterations of democratically elected governments, people&amp;rsquo;s involvement in democracy is just limited to general elections every 5 years. Very little occurs in between.
You see, in my view, Chile is a place where the government does pretty much whatever it wants once it&amp;rsquo;s in power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Static</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2014/03/going-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 16:54:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2014/03/going-static/</guid>
      <description>One reason why I had stopped posting anything in my blog for a while was my frustration on how slow the Wordpress back-end for Dreamhost “economy users” is, you know, the ones with the most basic plans.
I guess they must have realized that, since they are starting a new Wordpress-only hosting system, which is supposed to be optimized for that use only. All nice and good, but their promotional pricing of $19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook No More</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2013/09/facebook-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 10:20:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2013/09/facebook-no-more/</guid>
      <description>I resisted joining Facebook for quite some time, not because I’m a Luddite or an old timer, but rather because I know better than most people what goes on underneath the surface of such type of platforms. I also know well what happens to companies that become public and now face the constant pressure of produce results for the quarter. There is no free lunch…
However, most of my family in Chile, Europe and the USA have chosen that medium to communicate and share their daily lives and updates, without any regard for their sense of privacy or even a clear understanding of what they are giving away for the service they get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don&#39;t Use Gmail</title>
      <link>https://ramix.io/2013/07/why-i-dont-use-gmail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 15:35:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ramix.io/2013/07/why-i-dont-use-gmail/</guid>
      <description>I’ve never been very fond of keeping something as sensitive as my personal email in a service provider. I used to run my own email server at home based on Zimbra a few years back, but like everything else, it became cumbersome. Updates, backups and having to deal with restrictive ISP policies around SMTP made me finally give up and move all my 14 years of email to Google.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>